Mss.Rec.82 Mss.Rec.82
American Philosophical Society
- Northern Tepehuan material, 1951; Mss.Rec.82.6; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 8, track 1; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  The contents of this material are identical to APS Recording 12, tape 1, and therefore have not been digitized.
  Related Archival Materials
  See Northern Tepehuan language material (Mss.Rec.12)
  Sound recordings; Tepehuan Indians--Folklore; Tepehuan Indians--Music; Tepehuan language
- Southern Tepehuan material, 1948; Mss.Rec.82.7; 2.0 Reel(s); Spans tape 8, track 2 to tape 9, track 1, part 1; Mason, John Alden, 1885-1967
  The contents of this material are the same as that of APS Recording 11 and therefore have not been digitized.
  See Southern Tepehuan language material (Mss.Rec.11)
- Nahuatl texts, 1949; Mss.Rec.82.8; 1.0 Reel(s); Spans tape 9, track 1, part 2 to tape 9, track 2, part 1; Nahuatl Texts, recorded by Robert Barlow circa 1949, in Milpa Alta, Mexico. Stories given entirely in untranslated Nahuatl, with the exception of two stories given in Spanish. Almost all stories are given by Luz Jimenez. The identifiable texts include a story about the Mexican Day of the Dead holiday and the mountain Popocatepetl. Also includes one Yaqui song. There is occasional prominent cracking and hissing background noise on the recording.; Barlow, R. H., (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  Related Archival Material
  A typescript transcription of the stories given on the recording is available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics collection (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c).
  Originally APS Recording 6, recorded on six 78-rpm discs which were transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  Nahuatl Indians--Folklore; Sound recordings
  - Tlohkenawake (Dios sabio de todo) [1 of 2], 1949; 09-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:07; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
    Nahuatl Texts recorded by Robert Barlow circa 1949. Originally recorded on phonograph record, then transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970. Typescript transcript available in the Franz Boas Collection of Materials for American Linguistics (Call no.: Mss.497.3.B63c.)
    This file is a compressed, digitized version of the original. The APS Library maintains the original format (Phonograph record) as well as an uncompressed digitized version of this recording.
    Milpa Alta (Mexico); Nahuas--Folklore
  - Tlohkenawake (Dios sabio de todo) [2 of 2], 1949; 09-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:37; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Sasanili ipampa in mikailwitl [1 of 3], 1949; 09-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:47; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Sasanili ipampa in mikailwitl [2 of 3], 1949; 09-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:56; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Sasanili ipampa in mikailwitl [3 of 3], 1949; 09-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:48; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Kenin motamalchiwa, 1949; 09-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:18; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Las Flores (Totonaco), 1949; 09-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
    All Souls' Day; Milpa Alta (Mexico); Nahuas--Folklore; Totonac Indians--Folklore
  - Maso (Yaqui), 1949; 09-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:41; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951
    Milpa Alta (Mexico); Yaqui Indians--Music
  - Sasanili ipampa in teposton [1 of 2], 1949; 09-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:51; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Sasanili ipampa in teposton [2 of 2], 1949; 09-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:52; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Tewewentsin, 1949; 09-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:39; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Personajes en los cerros, 1949; 09-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Popokatepetl, 1949; 09-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:25; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Espinosa, Miguel Barrios
    Milpa Alta (Mexico); Nahuas--Folklore; Popocatépetl (Mexico)
  - Dios ometekwikatl [1 of 2], 1949; 09-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:02; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
  - Dios ometekwikatl [2 of 2], 1949; 09-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:40; Barlow, R. H. (Robert Hayward), 1918-1951; Jiménez Quispe, Luz
- Russian language folk material, undated; Mss.Rec.82.9; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 9, track 2, part 2; Excerpts of Russian wedding rite, followed by Russian folk songs sung by a group of women. No accomapnying documentation.
  Originally recorded on two 78-rpm discs, transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  Folk music--Russia (Federation); Marriage customs and rites--Russia; Sound recordings
  - Four excerpts from Russian wedding rite, Undated; 09-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:17
    Originally recorded on 78-rpm disc, transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
    Marriage customs and rites--Russia; Pskov (Russia); Wedding music--Russia (Federation)
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:11
    Folk music--Russia (Federation); Pskov (Russia)
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:09
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:49
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:30
  - Russian folk song, Undated; 09-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:01
- Ceremonial Songs of Tonawanda Seneca Longhouse, 1936; Mss.Rec.82.10; 2.0 Reel(s); Ceremonial Songs of Tonawanda Seneca Longhouse, recorded by Martha Champion Randle on phonograph discs in 1936. This material has access restrictions.; Cornplanter, Jesse J.; Randle, Martha Champion
  Typescript transcripts (56 p.) of a majority of the songs are available in the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection.
  To be used with: Kurath, Gertrude Prokosch. Ceremonial songs of Tonawanda Seneca Longhouse. (Mss.497.3.K965st)
  Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Sound recordings
  - Women's Dance, 1936; 09-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:40; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
    Originally recorded phonograph discs in 1936, then transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970. Typescript transcripts are available in the Miscellaneous Manuscripts collection.
    Seneca Indians--Music; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Hand in Hand Dance, 1936; 09-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:17; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Hand in Hand Dance, 1936; 10-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:18; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Hand in Hand Dance, 1936; 10-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:32; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Great Feather Dance, 1936; 10-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:47; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Great Feather Dance, 1936; 10-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:07; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - New type women's dance, 1936; 10-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:09; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - False Face, 1936; 10-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:46; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
    Seneca Indians--Music; Seneca Indians--Rites and ceremonies; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - False Face, 1936; 10-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:11; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - False Face, 1936; 10-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:01; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Drawing, 1936; 10-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Eagle Dance, 1936; 10-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:04; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Eagle Dance, 1936; 10-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:22; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Fish Dance, 1936; 10-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:57; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Pigeon Dance, 1936; 10-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:37; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - War Dance (Thunder Rite), 1936; 10-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:46; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Change Rib, 1936; 10-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:25; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Change Rib, 1936; 10-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:33; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Change Rib, 1936; 10-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:11; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Change Rib, 1936; 10-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:05; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Change Rib, 1936; 10-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Moccasin Game Songs, 1936; 10-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:47; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Dawn Songs, 1936; 10-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:05; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Coon Dance, 1936; 10-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:49; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Women's Dance, 1936; 10-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:04; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Feather Dance, 1936; 10-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:12; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Women's Dance, 1936; 10-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:41; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Buffalo Dance, 1936; 10-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:22; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Corn Dance, 1936; 10-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:43; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Corn Dance, 1936; 10-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:38; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Robin Dance, 1936; 10-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:12; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Duck Dance, 1936; 10-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:08; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - War Dance, 1936; 10-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:41; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Pigeon Dance, 1936; 10-32; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:13; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Devil Dance, 1936; 11-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:32; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Dark Dance, 1936; 11-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:57; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Dark Dance, 1936; 11-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Garters Dance, 1936; 11-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:50; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Garters Dance, 1936; 11-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:33; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Drum Dance, 1936; 11-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:13; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Drum Dance, 1936; 11-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:49; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Drum Dance, 1936; 11-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Drum Dance, 1936; 11-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:19; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - New Women's Dance, 1936; 11-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:59; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - New Women's Dance, 1936; 11-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:51; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - New Women's Dance, 1936; 11-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:04; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Women's Dance, 1936; 11-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:28; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Women's Dance, 1936; 11-14; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:44; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Trotting Dance, 1936; 11-15; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:29; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Trotting Dance, 1936; 11-16; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:00; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Trotting Dance, 1936; 11-17; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:26; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Chicken Dance, 1936; 11-18; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:16; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Yei'dos, 1936; 11-19; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:01; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Women's Dance with "Three Sisters", 1936; 11-20; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:53; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Adon'we: Personal Chants, 1936; 11-21; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:27; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Handsome Lake's Own Song, 1936; 11-22; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:46; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
    Handsome Lake, 1735-1815; Seneca Indians--Music; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Women's Dance at Seed Festival, 1936; 11-23; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:50; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Knee Rattle Dance, 1936; 11-24; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:33; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Pigeon Dance, 1936; 11-25; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:29; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Story song about a poor family, 1936; 11-26; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:52; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
    Seneca Indians--Folklore; Seneca Indians--Music; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Story song about a stuck-up boy, 1936; 11-27; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:07; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Moccasin Games, 1936; 11-28; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:54; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - False Face, 1936; 11-29; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:12; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Bear Dance, 1936; 11-30; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:29; Black, Edward; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Oh gi we: Dance For Departed Spirits, 1936; 11-31; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:50; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Oh gi we: Dance For Departed Spirits, 1936; 11-32; 1.0 .mp3; 00:05:11; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Oh gi we: Dance For Departed Spirits, 1936; 11-33; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:31; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Quavering, 1936; 11-34; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:02; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - New Fish Dance, 1936; 11-35; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:00; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Unidentified song, 1936; 11-36; 1.0 .mp3; 00:04:52; Randle, Martha Champion; Shanks, Robert
  - Choose a Partner Dance, 1936; 12-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:32; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Skin Beating Dance (Delaware), 1936; 12-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:32; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Sun Rite: Striking the Stick (Pole) Dance, 1936; 12-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:59; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Alligator Dance, 1936; 12-04; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:16; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Grinding an Arrow Dance, 1936; 12-05; 1.0 .mp3; 00:02:06; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Carry Out Kettle, 1936; 12-06; 1.0 .mp3; 00:03:45; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Oshewe, 1936; 12-07; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:45; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Husk Faces, Medicine Society Rite, 1936; 12-08; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:22; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Hiawataha Show Song, 1936; 12-09; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:21; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Funeral song from Hiawatha, 1936; 12-10; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:34; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
    Funeral music; Seneca Indians--Music; Tonawanda Indian Reservation (N.Y.)
  - Council Fire Song, 1936; 12-11; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:32; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Iroquois Dawn Song, 1936; 12-12; 1.0 .mp3; 00:01:56; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
  - Canoe or Hunting Song, 1936; 12-13; 1.0 .mp3; 00:00:52; Cornplanter, Jesse; Randle, Martha Champion
- Materials on Papiamento, native language of the Netherlands Antilles, circa 1962; Mss.Rec.82.11; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 13, track 1, part 1; Program consists of stories and songs, interspersed with organ and Latin American music. No accompanying documenation.; Forbes, Jacques C. B.
  Originally part of APS Recording 48, consisting of two 7" discs and one 10" disc transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congressin 1970.
  Papiamento; Songs, Papiamento; Sound recordings
  - Materials on Papiamento, circa 1962; 13-01; 1.0 .mp3; 00:50:41; Forbes, Jacques C. R.
    Program consists of stories and songs, interspersed with organ and Curacaoan music. Originally part of APS Recording 48, consisting of two 7" discs and one 10" disc transferred to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
    Curaçao; Organ music; Papiamento; Songs, Papiamento
- Reminiscences of Dr. Edwin Grant Conklin (1863-1952), Biologist, 1952 November 21; Mss.Rec.82.12; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 13, track 1; A group discussion with Professor Edwin G. Conklin on November 19, 1952, two days before his death.; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952; Frankhauser, Gerhard; Parpart, Arthur Kemble, 1903-1965
  Originally APS Recording 26, transferred from phonograph record to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
  American Philosophical Society; Biology--United States; Embryology--History; Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Mass.); Sound recordings
  - Reminiscences of Dr. Edwin Grant Conklin (1863-1952), Biologist [1 of 2], 1952-11-19; 13-02; 1.0 .mp3; 00:10:22; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952; Frankhauser, Gerhard; Parpart, Arthur Kemble, 1903-
    Reminiscences and group discussion, made two days before Dr. Conklin's death. Originally APS Recording 26, transferred from phonograph record to open reel tape for the APS by the Library of Congress in 1970.
    American Philosophical Society; Biology--United States; Embryology--History; Philadelphia (Pa.)
  - Reminiscences of Dr. Edwin Grant Conklin (1863-1952), Biologist [2 of 2], 1952-11-19; 13-03; 1.0 .mp3; 00:15:01; Conklin, Edwin Grant, 1863-1952; Frankhauser, Gerhard; Parpart, Arthur Kemble, 1903-
- Speech on the development of the Atomic Bomb by Robert J. Oppenheimer, circa 1946; Mss.Rec.82.13; 1.0 Reel(s); Tape 13, track 2, part 2; Oppenheimer, J. Robert, 1904-1967
  Atomic bomb--History; Sound recordings